Make sure that the band is secure up top.
You're going to take your elbows out and all we're going to do is lean back just a little bit so that we're in our motion so that from your shoulders to your hip are actually at a slant and you're not straight up and down with your body.
So, lean back into it just a little bit.
We're opening out; squeezing the shoulder blades down the spine.
All the way back, almost bringing the thumbs to your shoulders and then extension comes up.
We want to keep the resistance here, as opposed to letting the shoulders round out and let go of the tension.
So, apply the pressure, pull back and engage.
We're going to do this as a compound exercise so we do lats and traps, dropping down into a row.
So, our combination is going to go lat and row.
When you're doing your lats your elbows open wide.
When you're doing your row the elbows brush the rib cage.
If this is too easy for you go up to a red band.
This is going to add a little bit more resistance, and pull.
If it's still easy for you double up your bands and do both at the same time.
So, now we've got a really heavy load as we're working through those muscles.
We want to do reps to fatigue on this one.
If you've just started it's going to be about eight to twelve repetitions.
If you've been working out for a while really try to fail those muscle groups.
So, your goal is to really pull those shoulders back, so we're working deep into your lats.
The lats look like a triangle upside down.
So, we're trying to get all the way down into the lower portion of your back.
We're even trying to get up into your trap area.
So, as you're pulling back engage the muscles and then release it.
Sit up really tall and then lean back so that you've got your abs engaged the whole time.
That is how we do our lat pull down into a row combination using the stability ball or a chair or actually standing up and doing this if you don't have anything to sit on.
Either way will work.